[Music]
Hey Nathan, how are you doing? Hello.
Hello. Well, thank you so much for being
uh today on I believe um some of you
have mentioned that it was too late.
Well, for Nathan is too early. He is
calling from us from uh Australia. Is
that correct?
New Zealand actually New Zealand even
better. So um Nathan super excited to
have you uh on this conference. Uh I
know a lot of folks have been looking
forward to this uh session in
particular. So um I won't take any more
of your time and we'll leave you right
to it. Thank you very much and thanks
for the great intro. Um, it's kind of
funny to call ads a small startup, but I
think oftentimes some of my best work at
adabs has happened in these small teams,
the two pizza teams, and it feel like a
little startup inside of AWS. Um, so
today I'm going to show something which
I've been building uh using Amazon
Generative AI products for coding
assistance and it is a little game here
which uh you'll see this ghost character
and um the goal of this game is to be a
crafting game where where um I can get
some items out of a dispenser. I can
play around with them. I can pick them
up and inspect them and then then
eventually I'll be able to craft with
them.
Okay, so the hardest part of this game
ended up being the physics engine. And I
realized that generative AI has a really
hard time with coding physics engines.
And I figured I would take some of my
experiences here and show um how that
experience of coding a physics engine
works so you could maybe learn from it
and learn some of the t trip the tips
and tricks that I found to help gener
function better when coding difficult
things such as
this. So to start with let me open up
the codebase. Um you're going to see
Visual Studio Code here which is running
Amazon Q developer. This is a product
that I work on at Amazon and you may
have heard of it. Uh you may have seen
the part that runs in the console and
famously a lot of people
were widely uh ridiculing the answers
from the console piece. Well, we also
have a um IDE plugin which works a whole
lot better now. And that's what I've
been using to code this game and and
I've been trying to experiment with vibe
coding. 95% of the code actually been
written by Amazon Sue. So, let me first
check out the starter branch of this and
we're going to try to repro
um actually vibe coding the physics
engine from scratch. So, now that I've
reset it, I should be in here and I have
my character, but he can no longer move
around. He's kind of stuck in place.
Okay, let's see what we can do here. I
have a prompt I'm going to try first.
And I'm going to request that Amazon Q
build a physics simulation that allows
my uh character and game items to move
around. To start with, I'm going to open
up one of the files here, the game
items, so that way it has some more
information about how things are
structured. So, this is one of the first
things I realized with vibe coding
inside of an ID editor, which is that
it's important to sort of set the
context. Um, if I did not give any
context, then it's likely that this
agent here would be able to dig deep
into my codebase and find some files to
work off of and use as a basis for
developing this feature. However, this
codebase is quite large. There's a
client side application that has a bunch
of different assets and components, um,
helper functions, views. There's a
server side. There's infrastructure as
code. Um, the server has a bunch of
handlers, things for inter interacting
with LLMs, all kind of stuff. There's a
whole lot going on inside of this
codebase. And the more that I can get
the um AI agent to the right place to
start working earlier, um, the more
success we'll have at that. So you can
already start to see that if you are a
little bit more technical at uh with
your vibe coding and providing a
bootstrapping uh context for the AI
agent, you're going to get a lot better
results. Now Amazon Q has explored a
little bit deeper. It's looked at some
of the existing files that branching off
of this file. So for example, this is
one my one of my other tips here is
consider using a type language. So
you'll notice that here I have an
interface written in Typescript and
there's a physics defined here on this
this uh object and it's defined by this
um type physics properties. So based on
that it's been able to follow the link
over to this file physics.ts where the
interface is defined. It's discovered
that we have a placeholder here for how
we want the physics properties to be
defined but that's not implemented. So
based on that, it's dug in to the
codebase and it's decided to start
writing something is calling a physics
system. So here we get to rapid fire tip
number three. One of the things that I
realized early on working with
generative AI products for coding is
that they tend to stuff everything into
one
file. And and this is a problem because
the larger a file gets, the longer it
gets, the more tokens are in that file.
Um the more the context gets filled up
and actually the slower the AI agents
get. This is a problem because the more
tokens you have, the more you're
spending. Um and you're also spending a
lot on time. If you're winning on the AI
to go out and crunch, let's say 200,000
tokens, um you're waiting a lot longer
to get responses back. So one of the one
of the things that I've done is I've
followed some of like uh Martin Fowler's
best practices for dividing up a
codebase into decoupled components which
each handle a single thing. So here this
is handling the item system for the
game. This is handling the websocket
connection to the server. This is
handling keeping track of game objects.
And based on the fact that I have
already split this code up into these
decoupled modules that aren't uh talking
to each other, they're sort of
separated. The Q agent has determined
that this is how I would like to lay out
my product uh uh my project and it has
created its own decoupled physics
system. This physics system does
interact obviously with the game object
system, but it does so through a higher
level uh view reference. And so this
allows each of these individual files,
you'll see this one is only 51 lines.
The socket system is only one of the
larger ones is only 200 lines. So each
of the individual files in my codebase
ends up being um fairly
small. This the other technical choice
I've made in this codebase is to use the
Vue uh framework. If you're familiar
with React, Vue is very similar to it.
It's a reactive framework for front-end
development. And one of the things that
it allows you to do that's very
important is uh let me open a better one
here. Let's open up this one. It allows
you to keep the logic, the presentation
and the styling of a component all
together in one file. So here you'll see
that the JavaScript code for uh handling
the logic for this component is here.
The template for how to render it is
also here in the same file. And then the
CSS for how to style it is also all in
the same file.
So, because these things are are all
coupled together inside of a single file
component, it'll makes it a lot easier
for the agent to locate the things that
it needs and um and and work on those.
So, you can see the agent has gone to
work over here. It's added a physics
system. It's added imports. It's hooked
that physics system in. Um and it's also
added a debug panel. I'm going to go
ahead and stop this right now because
um you may be able to tell just by how
this is working here that it's it's
based on uh Claude Sonet 3.7. Cloud
Sonic 3.7 tends to go a little bit more
ambitious sometimes. It uh it really
decides to work really hard and really
deeply into your codebase. So, let me
refresh over here and see what what our
results are. And sure enough, our
character can now move around.
Um, we can also spit some items out of
dispenser. So, some of the physics are
working, but we have a problem here.
You'll notice that, um, it's a good
thing I picked a ghost character. Uh,
the ghost character is literally just
walking through the walls. Um, so this
this is the first problem that that I
discovered is that somehow the
uh the the AI agent doesn't tend to
understand that walls are something that
needs to be collided with. Um, it it has
something to do with the layout of my
codebase. So, let's see if we can ask
the AI to figure this out. So, I'm going
to say, uh, for some reason, my player
character is just walking through
through walls. How to fix this? Let's
see if we can figure it out. So, this
would be a typical debugging scenario.
Uh, this will be the let's say let's
call this the first hallucination, the
first the first serious problem that we
have in in the vibe coding here. And
this is going to highlight something
that is very important. Let's see if it
let's see if it comes to the right
solution. I already know what the
problem is because I I did manage to
code through this and get it working.
Um, let's see if it let's see if it
finds the right solution,
though. Meanwhile, I'm going to open up
this file here to show you how that the
game objects are initialized in this
world. And you'll notice that when I
create the walls, uh, the walls start
out with active false or physics
objects. and and this was intended as a
optimization where I didn't want it
recalculating physics too frequently for
items that are static. However, when it
implemented this physics system, uh
you'll notice that let's see, it's
probably had a check in here somewhere.
I haven't seen this code yet. Um yeah,
so physics objects, it's filtering out
where it's only considering objects that
have active physics. So essentially
what's happening is anything that um
anything that starts out in in active
state or eventually deactivates just
gets completely taken out of the
simulation and the character can just
walk through it. So this highlights the
importance of semantics and how you
define your API. I probably should have
caused called this something like paused
or something along those lines. But
because I chose the word active, the AI
has assumed that what I intended here
was that this thing should be completely
taken out of the sim the physics
simulation rather than than simply
paused for performance characteristics.
So, I'm gonna I'm gonna actually skip
ahead a little bit um to a separate
checkpoint
uh so I can show you um after I fix this
issue where we got
um
instead and I'll be able to highlight
some of the other what's going on here.
Oh, get
um clean. There we go. Okay. So, I'll
show you I'll show you the the working
physics state that I was able to get to
earlier. We've got a little bit further
in. Uh we can still spit items out. Uh
we do have walls that uh are here.
However, the issue is there the issues
aren't completely fixed. Um there's
still some problems in here and and I'll
show you what some of those problems
are. First is a performance issue. So,
you'll notice if you look very
carefully, it may not show up over the
stream, but objects just never stop
moving. they're just constantly bouncing
up and down a little bit. So, we fixed
that inactive physics bug, but in so
doing, we've we've ensured that objects
just never deactivate ever. And it at
first it took me a little bit of time to
figure out what was going on here. Then
I realized I should pop open the view
inspector and actually look at the the
data objects in here to see what it was
doing in these phys physics
calculations. And you'll notice
something very interesting. If I open
this up and look at physics, you'll see
that it has an extremely small
velocity. And that velocity just never
degrades. Um, it's just it's just always
slightly bouncing up and down. And then
eventually when it does degrade, what
happens? Once again, this object is like
completely static. I'm just bouncing off
of it. I'm not be able to move it. So,
we have a couple we have a couple
different bugs here that that are very
interesting. Let me show you another
one. This one is one of my favorites
because it is uh really easy to repro,
but it is a uh a classic bug that
happens in pretty much every old game.
It's so validating to see um uh the AI
making mistakes from classic old games.
So, what I've done is I've I've flipped
out to another tab and then when I go
back into my game, you're going to see
like this huge bounce and like one of
those objects just like flew up into the
air. Uh, and then if I watch this, if I
go down to the bottom and I'm pressing
against the wall and then I go over to
another
tab and then I tab back in sometimes.
Let me see. Maybe not, maybe not that
time. Let me go this like this. Okay.
So, so I have a velocity headed toward
the wall and then I tab back in. Uh, I
didn't I can't repro it reliably. It's
just like speedrunning uh tactics here.
Um, but basically you can you can click
clip through the wall if you start out
by moving toward the wall and then you
tab out to deactivate the browser tab
and then you then you tab back in. So So
what's going on there? So this is a
classic bug and I'm going to demonstrate
debugging uh using this particular bug
because it's a pretty fun one. I'm going
to
say sometimes when I tab out of the game
and then tab back
in, my character flips through the wall
or items bounce around like
crazy. How can I fix this?
So, the the thing you're going to
realize as I go through these different
debugging scenarios and and this
different hallucinations and mistakes
that that I'm showing here is that vibe
coding just isn't enough. Um, I I I wish
that these systems would be able to
implement something from scratch um in
in a single pass, a single shot that's
completely bug free, but the reality is
your attention to detail is super
important. um you have to be able to to
go in there and and test things and and
find performance issues and find places
where there are bugs and use your human
brain in conjunction with the vibe
coding prompt. Um this is something that
that I tell developers all the time
because there's a lot of marketing
messaging out there out there about AI
is coming from your job. You know, your
job is going to be taken away by by AI.
But the reality is um these tools are
still in need of a lot of human
assistance to figure out what's going
on. And so here you can see it has
helped me debug this though. It's saying
um when you tab out of the game and then
back in physics calculations can get
messed up because of large time deltas.
This happens because the browser might
pause or slow down the animation frames
when the tab's not in focus. So
basically when I tab out and tab back in
this time since the last physics update
is too large and therefore items sort of
leap forward so fast that they will go
completely through a wall or bounce into
each other extremely hard. So it's been
able to not only fix this, but it's also
adding a visibility state tracker. That
way when I tab out and tab back in, it's
going to pause the physics uh simulation
as well as doing something that's
causing maximum delta time camp uh time
cap, which is if the delta time is too
large, it's going to reduce it to lower
um
um lower delta. So, uh I'm out of time
now. I I'll switch over to Q&A, but I
hope that you were able to learn
something from watching me live build
and and debug here with the Amazon Q
developer agent. Um, if you liked what
you saw here, please consider installing
Amazon Q developer VS Code or the QCLI
and try it out and see whether this
agent is also useful for you in your
coding.
Thank you so much, Nathan. Uh, that was
so so insightful. uh like really really
appreciate uh you going with that and
what a fun little game like uh really
really uh cool to see some of these edge
cases. Um now we are unfortunately
running out of time and we're going to
have to switch into the next session.
However um please uh as you know all of
our guests are very happy to um you know
communicate with you offline on socials
and etc like this. So please like reach
out to them. Uh, but yeah, just wanted
to take a pause again. Like, thank you
so much, man. Like, that was super super
fun to to see. Thank you.